노려라! 천점만점! ~브레이브 성인(?) 등장~
Aim for the Perfect Score! ~Brave Seijin(?) appears~
대체 누구지? 텔레파시로 남극까지 부른 게... 분명, 중대한 요건이 있다고 했는데...
Who called me to the south pole via telepathy...? He said he got an important matter to discuss about....
잘 와 주었다, 미스터 라이언!
Good to have you here, Mister Lian!
음? 다, 당신은...!
Hm? Y- you must be...!
그렇다, 나는 브레이브 성인... 우주 경찰 기구의 형사...
Yes, I am Brave Seijin, a detective from the Space Police Organization.
그래서, 내게 볼 일은? 설마 아크 성인에게 복수하는 걸 그만하라는 둥은 아니겠지?
So, what do you want? I hope you didn't call me just to tell me to stop seeking revenge on Ark Seijin; did you?
널 방해할 생각은 없다... 고향의 원한은 그 손으로 갚으면 된다.
I have no intention to get in your way. Have your revenge for your home planet with your own your hands.
그럼 중대한 요건은 뭐냐?
Then, what's that important matter you said before?
아크 성인한테 복수를 하고 나면, 자네는 어떻게 할 생각인가?
After you have your revenge, what will you do?
흥, 당연하지 않나. 내 고향 검성을 재건할 것이다!
Hmph, you already know. I will take part in reconstruction of my home planet Kensei.
그렇군... 그렇지만 자네에게는 그 외에 해야만 하는 일이 있지 않은가?
I see... But don't you have something else that you must do?
해야만 하는 일?
Something I must do?
자네는 지금까지 다수의 우주 범죄자와 싸워 온 용감한 용사다.
You are a brave warrior who fought quite a number of space criminals.
그 힘을 앞으로도 지구의 평화를 위해 써 주었으면 한다.
I want you to use your power for the peace of the Earth.
그 말인즉슨...
That would mean...
우리 우주 경찰 기구의 일원이 되어 주기를 바란다!
I want you to become a member of the Space Police Organization.
내가? 우주 경찰 기구의 일원이?
Me? Become a member of the Space Police Organization?
그러고 보니, 어렸을 적에 크면 우주 경찰 기구에 들어가고 싶다고 생각을 했지... 그 때 꿈이 지금 이루어질 줄은...
When I was young, I always wanted to join the Space Police Organization when I grow up...
I never thought that dream would become true...
미스터 라이언. 자네가 좋다면 지금 즉시 입대 시험을 시작하고 싶다.
Mister Lian, I would like to begin the entrance exam right now, if you'd accept.
어? 음, 나는 괜찮다.
What? Well, I'm ready...
시험은 천점만점. 천점을 향해 힘내길 바란다.
The exam will be graded by score. Please do your best to achieve the perfect score.
바라던 바!
I sure will!
그럼 지구 문화에 대한 첫번째 질문.
Then, the first question will be on the culture of the Earth.
세계에서 제일...
What is the...
...높은 산은?
...highest mountain in the world?
에... 에베... 엘리베이터!
E... Ev... Elevator!
땡. 0점. 그럼 2번 질문. 토쿠가와 가 제 8대 장군의 이름은?
Bzzt. Zero points. For the second question, what is the name of the eight general of Tokugawa family?
하... 히... 히코자에몬!
Ha... Hi... Hikozaemon!
(Look up 徳川将軍一覧 in Japanese Wikipedia for the right answer; -gozaemon means drowned person)
땡. 0점. 그럼 계속해서 3번 질문. 27 곱하기 34는?
Bzzt. Zero points. We'll continue with the third question. What is 27 times 34?
어디, 배, 백, 칠백!
Err, hun- hundred... seven hundreds!
땡. 0점. 다음은 말끝잇기다. 이 쪽에서부터... 이루카(돌고래)!
Bzzt. Zero points. Following will be word chaining test. Let me begin by... Iruka(dolphin)!
카... 카메라!
Ka... Camera!
라쿠다(낙타)!
Rakuda(Camel)!
다, 다, 다그온!
Da... Da... Dagwon!
땡. 0점. 이번엔 빠르게 똑바로 말하기다.
아카마키가미 아오마키가미 키마키가미
(빨간 두루마리, 파란 두루마리, 노란 두루마리)
Bzzt. Zero points. This time, it will be swift pronunciation challenge.
akamakigami aomakigami kimakigami
(red roll paper, blue roll paper, yellow roll paper)
아카마키마키 아오마키가키 키마키마키키츠즈키
(아카마키가미 아오마키가미 키마키가미)
akamakimaki aomakigaki kimakimakikitsuzuki
(akamakigami aomakigami kimakigami)
땡. 0점...
Bzzt. Zero points...
아, 미스터 라이언, 미안하지만 이번 이야기는 없던 일로 하지 않겠나.
Well, Mister Lian, I regret to inform you that my offer is now void.
그, 그런! 내가 불합격이라는 건가!?
N- no way! Are you telling me that I didn't pass!?
이렇게는 확실히 말이지... 그렇지만, 그 성적을 만회할 수 있는 방법이 하나 있다.
With a performance like that, definitely... But, there is one way that you can redeem your score.
무슨 방법이냐? 어서 말해라! 난 무엇이든 하겠다!
What would that be? Tell me! I'll do anything!
그들을... 다그온을 하나도 남기지 말고 매장하는 것이다.
Get rid of them... Get rid of the Dagwons without leaving one alive.
뭣이? 다그온을? 그렇지만 그들은...
What? Dagwons? But they're...
분명 그들은 내가 고른 용자다.
I admit that they are the brave warrios that I chose.
그렇지만 그 때는 시간이 없어서 말이지... 나로써도 본의가 아니었다.
But, I didn't have enough time back then. It wasn't what I was going for.
그렇다고 해도...
But still...
아니다! 불량품은 없애야 한다! 그리고 지금이야말로 참된 용자가 될 인재를...
Wrong! Defective ones must be disposed! The time has came to pick the right persons of talent who'll become the new brave warriors....
새로운 다그온을 뽑을 때가 온 것이다! 물론, 자네는 이미 뽑혀 있지, 미스터 라이언!
It's time to pick new Dagwons! Of course, you are already as good as picked, Mister Lian!
내가? 이 내가 새로운 다그온이?
Me? I'll become a new Dagwon?
그렇다! 가라! 가서 놈들을 쓰러트려라!
Right! Go! Go and take them down!
음, 알겠다...
Err, alright!
그렇지만 그 전에 하나 물어볼 것이 있다.
But before that, I have one question to ask.
음?
Hm?
다그온들은 당신들 언어로 용자를 의미하는 것 같은데...
It seems that Dagwon means brave warrior in your language...
당신 자신은 붓친팟친페로페로피인가?
Are you a bucchinpacchinperoperopii yourself?
음... 그, 그건...
Um... Well, that's...
나는 아무리 봐도 당신이 붓친팟친페로페로피로밖에 보이지 않는다만.....
No matter how I look at, you simply look like a bucchinpacchinperoperopii and nothing else...
설마, 자신의 행성의 언어를 잊었다고 하진 않겠지...?
Could it be that you forgot the language of your very own planet?
마, 말도 안 되는 소리를! 그렇고말고, 네 말대로 나는 붓친팟친페로페로피다!
D- don't say stupid! Yes, definitely right, as you said, I am a bucchinpacchinperoperopii!
흥, 역시 그렇군... 그러면 그냥 넘어갈 수는 없지.
Hmph, just as I thought... Then, I can't let this pass.
체인지! 라이오 소드!
Change! Lio Sword!
정체를 드러내라, 사르갓소의 우주인!
Show yourself, Sargasso alien!
가, 갑자기 뭔 소리여?
W- what kind of nonsense are you talking 'bout!?
붓친팟친페로페로피는 브레이브 성인의 언어로 새빨간 가짜를 말하지.
Bucchinpacchinperoperopii means a fake caught red-handed!
하하하하하하! 뜻밖의 곳에서 결점을 들켰구나!
Hahahahahaha! What a surprising flaw it would have been to you!
히익, 그랬구먼! 그, 당신, 잠깐 진정하쇼. 이야기하면 풀려.
Damn, so that's what it meant! Hey, you, calm down for a bit. We'll have to talk 'bout this!
문답무용!
Talk to the judge instead!
정말이지 민낯 한번 못생겼군. 진짜하고는 완전 딴판이야.
What an unsightly look. He's not even close to the real one.
이런 놈한테 속다니, 나도 아직 갈 길이 멀군.
And to be fooled by someone like that... I ain't experienced enough yet.
그렇지만 우주 경찰 기구에 들어간다는 아이디어는 나쁘지 않을 지도 모른다.
But it might not be a bad idea to join the Space Police Organization.
지금부터 시험 공부라도 해 둘까.
Maybe I should start preparing for the exam.